Finding Aid for the Getty Research Institute Scholars Program Images and Recordings, 1985-2013 IA20026
Institutional Records and Archives
- Audio recordings, 1987-2001; Series I.; 21.7 Linear Feet (27 boxes); 1741.37 GB (944 files)
  - Scholar Year 1992-1993, Series I.G.; 53.68 GB (54 files)
    - Renaissance to Risorgimento: Franklin Murphy Symposium, with H. George Fletcher, T. Kimball Brooker, James Wells, and Robert Middlekauff, October 15, 1992; Series I.G.2.; (3 audiocassettes)
      Materials comprise audio recordings of a symposium held on October 15, 1992 that was part of a city-wide celebration of art historian and former UCLA Chancellor and Getty Trustee Franklin D. Murphy's 75th birthday. The symposium coincided with "Renaissance to Risorgimento: An Exhibition of Italian Books and Manuscripts" that was on display at the Getty in honor of Dr. Murphy. This event was part of the Getty Scholar Year 1992/1993, which was themed "The Metropolis as Crucible."
      - Session introduction, 0352a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
      - Flectcher, H. George [The role of the Morgan and the Morgan library as American collector of rare books], 0352a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
      - Brooker, T. Kimball, 0352b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
      - Discussion Session for Flecher and Brooker, 0353a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
      - Wells, James [Lecture on private collection during Franklin Murphy Symposium.], 0353a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
      - Middlekauf, Robert., 0354b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
      - Discussion Session for Wells and Middlekauff., 0354a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
    - L.A. Public Programming. Jodo Shu Temple, March 4, 1993; Series I.G.3.; (2 audiocassettes and 2 sets of copies)
      Materials comprise audio recordings of discussions and lectures related to the performance, "Perspectives on LA at the Jodo Shu Betsuin Buddhist Temple," which was part of a series of public programs in downtown Los Angeles that coincided with the Getty/ CalArts joint conference on "The Aesthetics of Community-Based Art Making." The intent of the event was to discuss issues raised by the arts with respect to culture, identity, democracy, and education, while considering the arts as an agent of cultural change. This event was part of the Getty Scholar Year 1992/1993, which was themed "The Metropolis as Crucible."
      - Roberto Bedoya [Session introduction], 0392a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Gina and Marcy on Marcy's video, 0392a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Daniel Marceo and Kimiko Roberts video presentation, 0392a3 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Hasenflow, Sanchez, and Clay [presentation on their videos], 0392a4 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Session discussion, 0392a5 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Martinez, Ruben [Performance lecture], 0392b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Panel dialogue on the idea of citizenship and art, 0393a (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
    - Lectures and presentations, Series I.G.4.
      - Wolf, Gerhard. "Mit sprache, gegen sprache (On Contemporary Experimental Literature in Germany),", January 7, 1993; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Heiman, Herb. Lecture Introduction, 0376a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Wolf, Gerhard. Part 1, 0376a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Wolf, Gerhard. Part 2, 0376b (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Wolf, Gerhard. Part 3, 0377a (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - LeFalle-Collins, Lizzetta, Paul Schimmel, Maurice Tuchman, Marcia Tucker. "On Contemporary Art: The Curator," Panel Discussion, January 25, 1993; (2 audiocassettes and 1 set of copies)
        - Session Introduction, 1993; 0384a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Tuchman, Maurice. Lecture "On Contemporary Art: The Curator.", 0384a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - LeFalle-Collins, Lizzetta. Schimmel, Paul. Tucker, Marcia. Lecture. "On Contemporary Art: The Curator.", 0384a3 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Panel Discussion. Part 1, 0384b (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Panel Discussion. Part 2, 0385 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Komar, Vitaly and Alexander Melamid. Lecture, February 11, 1993; (1 audiocassette and 1 copy)
        - Session introduction, 0389a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Komar, Vitaly and Alexander Melamid. Joint Lecture on Capitalist Art, 0389a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Ligeti, Gyorgy. "Trio for Violin, Horn and Piano," Performance and Discussion, February 23, 1993; (2 audiocassettes)
        - Lecture Introduction, 0391a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Ligeti, Gyorgy. "Trio for Violin, Horn and Piano" Performance, 0391a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Ligeti, Gyorgy. "Trio for Violin, Horn and Piano." Lecture, 0391a3 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Lecture Discussion, 0390a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - MADRES (Mothers and Daughters Reaching Empowered States). Aesthetics of Community Based Art Making: "From the Margins to Center Stage,", March 6, 1993; (1 audiocassette)
        - Introduction on MADRES [first few minutes of recording is contaminated with noise], 0398a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Performance on "From the Margins to Center Stage" by MADRES, 0398a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Corboz, André. "On the Cultural Sources of the American Territorial Grid: Thomas Jefferson and the Land Ordinance of 1784,", March 8, 1993; (1 audiocassette)
        - Introduction, 0399a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Lecture, 0399a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Audience questions, 0399b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Fabian, Johannes. "Beyond the 'Written' and the 'Oral': Performance and the Production of History in Popular Painting,", April 26, 1993; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Introduction, 0404a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Lecture, 0404a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Audience questions, 0404b1
      - Von Moos, Stanislaus. "The Museum and the City at the End of the Twentieth Century,", April 27, 1993; 0405a1; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Goodman, Mark. "Coming of Age: Millerton, New York, 1971-1991,", May 20, 1993; (1 audiocassette)
        - Project Introduction, 0406a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Lecture, 0406a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Audience Discussion, 0406b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Wolf, Christa. "Nagelprobe,", May 24, 1993; (1 audiocassette)
        - Lecture, 0407a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Audience discussion, 0407b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Reed, Marcia. "Works in Progress: Documents in Contemporary Art in the Center's Collections,", May 28, 1993; (1 audiocassette).
        The end of the introduction is missing. The beginning of the lecture is missing.
        - Session introduction, 0408a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
        - Lecture, 0408a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
      - Werckmeister, Otto Karl. "Straightforward Art History,", 1993
        - Otto, Karl. "Straightforward Art History,", June 7, 1993; 0410a; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-10)
  - Scholar Year 1993-1994, Series I.H.; 282.19 GB (172 files)
    Materials comprise audio recordings of events, lectures, and discussions held at the Getty during the scholar year 1993/1994. The theme for the year was "The Americas." Scholars researched varied aspects of the cultures of the Americas, from Pre-Columbian times to the present and their contributions and addressed issues related to empire, colonialism, diasporas, and cultural contact, as well as the impact of these events on artistic and cultural production.
    - Sexual Illegals, Barbershop Soundscape, Hittite Empire, September 7, 1993; Series I.H.1.
      Materials comprise audio recordings of an event held at the Getty during the scholar year 1993/1994 under the theme "The Americas." The recordings capture African American male poets/writers each telling a "story" or reciting a poem about an experience from their own lives and discussing why that memory is meaningful to them. Following individual readings is a discussion between writer-director Keith Antar Mason, professional barbers, and participating poets revealing the barbershop as central to African American culture--a place where men experience symbolic rites of passage and bond as they share experiences, folklore, and milestones in their lives.
      The Getty documented the Hittite Empire theater troupe's process of connecting the oral history tradition transposed from Africa to L.A.'s urban barbershops. Keith Antar Mason's research on barbershops was the basis for a theater piece, "Sexual Illegals," performed by the Hittite Empire, which was one of five Memory Projects commissioned as part of the 1993 L.A. Festival. The recordings herein are related to this performance, but do not document it.
      - Datcher, Michael., 0414a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
      - Toney, A.K. [Barbershop.], 0414b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
      - [Nebuy, Nafeese?], 0414c (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
      - Discussion., 0414d (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
    - Women's Voices: Readings and Dialogue, September 12, 19, 1993; Series I.H.2.; (2 miniature audiocassettes)
      Materials comprise audio recordings of readings and conversation with women writers captured in September of 1993. The event was part of a series of readings by women writers, "New Voices/New Perceptions: Conversations among Women Writers of Los Angeles, Africa, and the Middle East" featuring prominent women writers. The complete series took place in August and September of 1993 and was co-sponsored by the Getty, the Los Angeles Festival, and the Lannan Foundation.
      - Dialogue and Exchange with: Salma Jayyusi, Gwendolyn Brooks, Shirley Kaufman, Naomi Shihab Nye, Partow Nooriala, Robin Podolsky and Saudra Sharpe, September 12, 1993
        - Part a, 0416a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Part b, 0416b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
      - Dialogue and Exchange with: bell hooks, Thulani Davis, [Jessica Vangone?], Eloise Klein-Healy, June Jordan, Jacki Apple and Johanne Todd, September 19, 1993
        - Part a, 0417a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Part b, 0417b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
    - Power and Responsibility, September 30-October 2, 1993; Series I.H.3.; (10 audiocassettes)
      Materials comprise 1993 audio recordings of a symposium that explored questions about the nature of museums, their origins, their authority to "speak" on behalf of the populace, and the relationship of these issues to concepts of power. Issues are addressed from different perspectives influenced by various social, economic, and political conditions.
      Participants included an international group of arts administrators, artists, curators, and critics who discuss issues of access to cultural decision-making, relationships between public and private spheres, questions of audience and community, and ethical concerns about the control of distribution of works of art, images, and ideas.
      Panelists included David Avalos, visual artist, Los Angeles; Marie Claude-Beaud, Cartier Foundation, France; Olivier Debroise, novelist and culture critic, Mexico; Tom Finkelpearl, Public Arts Program, New York; Felix Gonzalez-Torres, artist, Group Material USA, New York; Vasif Kortun, curator, Istanbul; James Luna, artist, La Jolla Reservation, California; Declan McGonagle, Museum Director, Dublin, and others.
      The symposium was planned jointly by the Getty, the California Institute for the Arts, and the Museum of Contemporary Art.
      - Access, Institutional Power and Responsibility, September 30, 1993 (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Introduction, 0418a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Abalos, David T. [Relationship between institutions and the public; support for all cultures of art], 0418b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Dunning, Jeanne. "The Anonymous Museum" [project], 0419a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - McGonagle, Declan. [Lecture on reconsidering and redefining an inheritance in Dublin: socially, politically, and culturally], 0419b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Rose, Terry. [Lecture on museum institutions and the Los Angeles festival], 0420a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Discussion, 0420b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
      - Audience and Community, October 1, 1993 (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Introduction, 0424a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Guerra, Haridimos [?] "Power and the Intercultural Circulation of Art", 0424b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Kortun, Vasif. [Lecture on exhibition: confrontation, questioning, and experimentation], 0424c (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Lina, James.? [Lecture on the representation of Indians], 0424d (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Higa, Karin. [Lecture on ethnic groups and identities], 0424e (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Discussion, 0424f (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
          Recording of discussion is incomplete.
      - Distribution and the Circulation of Ideas, October 1, 1993 (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Introduction, 0421a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Du Bois, Oliviae. [Lecture on retention of power and self-consciousness: the real object of power], 0421b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Klonaridis, Caroline. [Lecture on single channel videos of art: media programs and support], 0422a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Arefin, Tony. [Lecture on city technology and interactive media: accessibility], 0422b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Neri, Louise. [Lecture on Parkett Magazine: interlocking issues in the art world], 0423a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Discussion, 0423b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
      - Public and Private Spheres of Interest, October 2, 1993 (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Introduction, 0425a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Funnell, Martha. "One Heart", 0425b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Nathan?. [Lecture on Y Corp?], 0425c (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Finkelpearl, Tom. [Lecture on public, private, and community: class], 0426a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Gonzalez-Torres, Felix. [Lecture on culture: public construction], 0426b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Clippel, Nemuri [?] [Lecture on power and responsibility], 0427a (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
        - Discussion, 0427b (Box 1996.IA.02-11)
    - Cine City: Film and Perceptions of Urban Space, 1895-1995, March 28-March 31, 1994; Series I.H.4.; (14 audiocassettes)
      Materials comprise audio recordings of lectures from "Cine City: Film and Perceptions of Urban Space, 1895-1995," a symposium that explored film's role in visualizing the future and how architecture has affected the evolution of film. The five-day international symposium brought together architects, filmmakers, production designers, and architecture and film historians to examine the city as represented in film and its relationship to built form. The symposium was held in 1994 in conjunction with a two-week series of film screenings organized by the Getty that included documentaries, feature films, and experimental films.
      - Cine City use copies, (4 CDs) (Enclosure 1996.IA.02-36)
      - Session 1: Cinema and the Construction of the Future, March 28, 1994
        - Vidler, Anthony. [Lecture on film and how it anticipates metropolitan architecture and discussion of this and preceding lectures.], 0469 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Koch, Gertrud. [Lecture on face-to-face communication, the cinema, and early construction of city life.], 0470a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Bruno, Guiliana. "Siteseeing: Architecture, Tourism, and the Moving Image.", 0470a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Response to Koch and Bruno lectures (unidentified speaker)., 0470b (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Gunning, Tom. "Kaleidoscope and X-Ray.", 0471a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Tsivian, Yuri. [Lecture on how architectural images of the future translate into film.], 0471a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Panel discussion and audience questions., 0471b (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
      - Session 2, March 29, 1994
        - Kaes, Anton. Session introduction: [A city signified, reading the urban text.], 0472a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Noma, Fertz. [Lecture.], 0472a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Dimendberg, Ed. [Lecture.], 0472b (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Zelinksi, Siegfried. [Stair formation as primal artifact of film architectonic.], 0473a (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Discussion and audience questions., 0473b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Weihsmann, Helmut (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
          - [Presentation on el bongard film], Part 1, 0473b2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
          - [Presentation on el bongard film], Part 2, 0474a (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Discussion and audience questions., 0474b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Farocki, Harun. [Lecture.], 0474b2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Fung, Hsin-Ming. [Lecture on the media and the making of architecture.], 0475a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Pat, O'Neill (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
          - [Lecture], Part 1, 0475a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
          - [Lecture], Part 2, 0475b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Audience questions, 0475b2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
      - Session 3, March 30, 1994
        - White, Ian Boyd. [Introduction.], 0476a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Bosselmann, Peter. [Lecture on urban architecture and film: consequences of design and planning.], 0476a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Lunenfeld, Peter. [Lecture on the theory of imaging and technology.], 0476b (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Hubert, Christian. [Lecture on hypertext; a model of cities and urban spaces.], 0477a (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Stone, Allucquere Rosanne [Sandy]. [Lecture on prosthetic devices and their influence in electronic communities & architectural structures.], 0477b (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Bukatman, Scott. [Introduction.], 0478a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Trumbull, Douglas. [Lecture on multimedia environments: computerated designs and manufacturing in cinema.], 0478a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Mead, Syd. [Lecture on problems of design and familiarity and unfamiliarity and design in the future.], 0478b (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Rashid, Hani. [Lecture on interface with the non-utopian spaces of Los Angeles.], 0479a (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Panel discussion and audience questions., 0479b (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
      - Session 3 [continued], March 31, 1994
        - Reese, Thomas F. and David Jensen. [Introduction.], 0480a (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Sekula, Alan. [Lecture on maritime space: spacial extremes of panorama and encapsulation.], 0480b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Lord, Catherine. [Lecture on making the earth move: sexual minorities in Los Angeles.], 0480b2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Burnett, Charles. [Lecture on minorities and racism and their representation in film and art.], 0481a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Response to the first panel., 0481a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Dear, Michael. [Lecture on the spaces and meanings of Los Angeles; and the struggles on the modes of representation.], 0481b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Hayden, Dolores. [Lecture on cultural landscape: history, identity, and urban design.], 0481b2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - James, David E. "Los Angeles: The Most Typical Avant-Garde.", 0482a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Israel, Franklin. [Lecture on his transformation of exposure to the film industry in Los Angeles.], 0482a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Final Discussion., 0482b (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
    - Imaging the City in the Americas: The Formation and Display of Urban Identity around 1910, Series I.H.5.
      Materials comprise 1994 audio recordings of seminars that launched a continued lecture series, "Imaging the City in the Americas.. ." The prototypical seminar was developed by GRI Deputy Director Thomas Reese and a Getty research group that included Claudia Bohn-Spector, Research Project Analyst; Wim De Wit, Head of Special Collections; Margarita Gutman, Getty Scholar, 1993-1994; and Carol McMichael Reese, Scholar Associate. According to Reese, "the research focus of the seminar [was] to consider how the image of the American city came into being and how it functioned in the construction of civic identities. In a multidisciplinary and comparative approach to the subject, and within the context of social, political, and economic conditions of urbanization, the seminar [focused] on selected cities that experienced rapid demographic change and economic expansion in the early 20th century, in order to examine the relationship between the politics of their development and their visual representation in popular culture, art, and literature. The objective [was] to illuminate not only the means by which ideas and images of urban form were constructed for, as well as by, various urban constituencies, but also the full range of modernist technologies that were harnessed for these purposes. Initial seminar sessions focused on Mexico City, Buenos Aires, and Los Angeles."
      - Reese, Carol McMichael and Thomas Reese. "Revolutionary Urban Legends: Porfirio Diaz's Celebrations of the Centennial of Mexican Independence in 1910,", March 15, 1994; (3 audiocassettes)
        - Part 1, 0463 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Part 2, 0464a (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Part 3, 0464b (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Part 4, 0465 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
      - Gutman, Margarita. "Idealizing the City: Anticipating the Future and Constructing Public Space in Buenos Aires in 1910," Lecture and Discussion, April 13, 1994; (3 audiocassettes)
        - Lecture, Part 1, 0486 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Discussion, Part 2, 0487a (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Discussion, Part 3, 0487b (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
        - Discussion, Part 4, 0488 (Box 1996.IA.02-12)
      - Deverell, William, Becky Nicolaides and Martin Padget. "Shaping Identities and Exporting the Image of Los Angeles: Metropolitan Image-Making and its Role on the Local, National and International Stage,", April 29, 1994; (3 audiocassettes)
        - Deverell, William. Part 1, 0499a (Box 1996.IA.02-13)
        - Padget, Martin. Part 2, 0499b (Box 1996.IA.02-13)
        - Nicolaides, Becky. Part 3, 0500 (Box 1996.IA.02-13)
        - Discussion. Part 4, 0501a (Box 1996.IA.02-13)
        - Discussion. Part 5, 0501b (Box 1996.IA.02-13)
      - Kristal, Efrain. "The Pampa and the Ethos of Buenos Aires,", May 25, 1994; (3 audiocassettes)
        - Kristal, Efrain. Part 1, 0517 (Box 1996.IA.02-14)
        - Discussion. Part 2, 0518a (Box 1996.IA.02-14)
        - Discussion. Part 3, 0518b (Box 1996.IA.02-14)
        - Discussion. Part 4, 0519 (Box 1996.IA.02-14)
      - Toscano, Alejandra Moreno. Introduction to screening of Memorias de un Mexicano, June 6, 1994; 0521; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-14)
      - Bohn-Spector, Claudia; Aurelio de los Reyes; Cristina Cuevas-Wolf; and Ulrich Keller. "Viewing the City: The Representation of American Cityscapes in Photography and Film,", June 7, 1994; (2 audiocassettes)
        - de los Reyes, Aurelio. Part 1, 0522a (Box 1996.IA.02-14)
        - Cuevas-Wolf, Cristina. Part 2, 0522b (Box 1996.IA.02-14)
        - Bohn-Spector, Claudia. Part 3, 0522c (Box 1996.IA.02-14)
        - Keller, Ulrich. Part 4, 0522d (Box 1996.IA.02-14)
        - Discussion. Part 5, 0523 (Box 1996.IA.02-14)
    - Fifteenth-Century Flemish Portraiture, Seeries I.H.6.
      Materials comprise audio recordings of a series of instructional lectures presented by art historian Linda Seidel during the scholar year 1993/1994. These five lectures, although hosted by the Getty, were thematically unrelated to other events that year; they were part of a graduate seminar taught by Professor Seidel at UCLA. The lectures focus on Flemish portraiture in the 15th century with significant attention paid to the Arnolfini Wedding Portrait, Ghent Altarpiece, and Freidsam Annunciation by Jan Van Eyck. Lectures touch on work by Robert Campin, Willem van Haecht, and many others. Seidel also discusses Erwin Panofsky's book Early Netherlandish Painting, explores relationships between the writings of Pliny and Flemish painting, and talks about the influences of the culture and religion of the 15th century upon the paintings of the time.
      - Seidel, Linda. "Mirrors of Meaning: Marriage as Metaphor,", April 20, 1994; (2 audiocassettes and 1 set of copies)
        - Part 1, 0495 (Box 1996.IA.02-13)
        - Part 2, 0496 (Box 1996.IA.02-13)